Guide to the Miriam J. Benkovitz Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Miriam J. Benkovitz Papers
1954-1986.
Benkovitz, Miriam J.
13,5 linear ft (ca. 9,100 items in 32 boxes).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
MS#0101
4078540
This collection contains correspondence, manuscripts, notes, notebooks, photographs, microfilm, and printed materials relating to Miriam J. Benkovitz, professor of English, Skidmore College.
Biographical Note
Miriam J. Benkovitz, professor of English, Skidmore College, and author. She colleceted books avidly, specializing in turn-of-the-century literature.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, notes, notebooks, photographs, microfilm, and printed materials relating to Benkovitz's scholarly activities, including her biographies of Aubrey Beardsley, Ronald Firbank and Frederick Rolfe (Baron Corvo), her bibliography of Firbank, as well as two books of Richard Aldington's correspondence which she edited, and numerous articles. Her correspondence is both personal and professional. The manuscripts are in various stages of completion, and include Benkovitz's many annotations and corrections. For the Aldington and Corvo notes, there are typescript copies of letters with extensive notes by Benkovitz. There are both personal photographs and photographs intended to illustrate her books.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in one series:
Series I: Miriam J. Benkovitz Papers, 1954-1986
Box 1: Arranged correspondence A-Z; Boxes 2-6: Richard Aldington; Boxes 7-10: Aubrey Beardsley Biography; Boxes 11-16: Baron Corvo Biography; Boxes 17-19: Ronald Firbank Bibliography; Box 20: Ronald Firbank Bibliography Supplement and 2nd Edition; Boxes 21-26: Ronald Firbank Biography; Boxes 27-29: Lord Ronald Gower Biography (unpublished); Boxes 30-31: Miscellaneous Articles; Box 32: Miscellaneous photographs, microfilm, and printed matter.
Subjects
Aldington, Richard, 1892-1962--Correspondence.; Beardsley, Aubrey, 1872-1898--Biography.; Firbank, Ronald, 1886-1926--Bibliography--Biography.; Rolfe, Frederick, 1860-1913--Biography.; Authors, English--20th century--Biography.; Correspondence; Photoprints; Biographers; College teachers
Acquisition
05/18/87 M-87-05-18 Feinberg, Miriam J. Gift
Gift of Miriam J. Feinberg, 1987.
- Series I: Miriam J. Benkovitz Papers, 1954-1986
  - Correspondence A-Z.
    - A (Box 1)
    - B (Box 1)
    - Bird, Alan (Box 1)
    - C (Box 1)
    - Clodd, Alan (Box 1)
    - D (Box 1)
    - F (Box 1)
    - G (Box 1)
    - H (Box 1)
    - K (Box 1)
    - L (Box 1)
    - Lambert, Jean (Box 1)
    - M (Box 1)
    - N-P (Box 1)
    - R (Box 1)
    - S (Box 1)
    - Sims, George and Beryl (Box 1)
    - T (Box 1)
    - Trevelyan, Raleigh (Box 1)
    - U-W (Box 1)
    - Weeks, Donald (Box 1)
    - unidentified correspondence (Box 1)
  - Richard Aldington
    - Correspondence
      - not dated (Box 2)
      - 1963-65 (Box 2)
      - 1967-71 (Box 2)
      - 1974 (Box 2)
      - 1976-78 (Box 2)
      - 1980-86 (Box 2)
      - Norman Gates correspondence (Box 2)
    - Manuscripts--Drafts
      - Introduction to A Passionate Prodigality (Box 3)
      - Introduction to Selected Letters of Richard Aldington (Box 3)
      - Selected Letters of Richard Aldington (Box 3)
      - Bibliographical Glossary for Selected Letters of Richard Aldington (Box 3)
      - Index and Bibliogranhical Glossary for Selected Letters of Richard Aldington (Box 3)
    - Notes
      - Notes (Box 4)
      - Typed copies of Aldington's correspondence with MJB's notes (Folders 1-8) (Box 5, Folder 1 to 8)
      - Typed copies of Aldington's correspondence with MJB's notes (Folders 9-16) (Box 6, Folder 9 to 16)
    - Negatives (Box 6)
  - Aubrey Beardsley Biography
    - Correspondence and Manuscripts
      - Correspondence
        - 1961 (Box 7)
        - 1977-1981 (Box 7)
      - Drafts (Folders 1-3) (Box 7, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Manuscripts
      - Drafts (Folders 4-7) (Box 8, Folder 4 to 7)
      - Typescripts (Box 8)
    - Galleys Photographs, Photocopied Material (Box 9)
    - Notes. (Box 10)
  - Baron Corvo Biography
    - Correspondence and Manuscripts
      - Correspondence
        - 1969-86 (Box 11)
      - Drafts
        - Folders 1-2 (Box 11, Folder 1 to 2)
        - Forward (Box 11)
        - Introduction (Box 11)
        - Venetian Letterbook Section (Box 11)
        - Endnotes (Box 11)
    - Manuscripts
      - Drafts
        - complete (Box 12)
        - pp. 1-306 (Box 12)
        - pp. 307-end (Box 13)
    - Proofs and Notes
      - Proofs (Box 13)
      - Notes (Box 13)
      - Notes
        - Copies of Corvo' s correspondence with MJB's notes (Box 13-14)
        - Typed copies of Corvo's correspondence from his letter book with MJB's Notes (Box 14)
      - Notes (Box 15-16)
    - Printed Materials, Negatives and Microfilm (Box 16)
  - Ronald Firbank Bibliography
    - Correspondence
      - not dated (Box 17)
      - 1954 (Box 17)
      - 1958-63 (Box 17)
      - Stuart Rose correspondence (Box 17)
    - Drafts Galleys and Proofs
      - Drafts (Folder 1) (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Drafts (Folders 2-4) (Box 18, Folder 2 to 4)
      - Galleys (Box 18)
      - Proofs (Box 18)
      - Notes (Box 19)
  - Ronald Firbank Bibliography Supplement and Ronald Firbank Bibliography, 2nd. Edition (Box 20)
    - Ronald Firbank Bibliography Supplement:
      - Correspondence
        - 1974-79 (Box 20)
      - Drafts (Folders 1-2) (Box 20, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Proofs (Box 20)
    - Ronald Firbank Bibliography, 2nd. Edition:
      - Correspondence
        - 1978-82 (Box 20)
      - Drafts (Folders 1-5) (Box 20, Folder 1 to 5)
      - Proofs (Box 20)
      - Printed and Photocopied Material (Box 20)
      - Marked copy of 1st. Edition (Box 20)
  - Ronald Firbank Biography
    - Correspondence
      - not dated (Box 21)
      - 1963-77 (Box 21)
      - Letters of congratulations April 1969-March 1972 (Box 21)
    - Manuscripts
      - Drafts (Folders 1-3) (Box 22, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Drafts (Folders 4-5) (Box 23, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Drafts, Galleys, Proofs and Notes (Box 24)
    - Notes (Box 25)
    - Notes, Negatives and Clippings (Box 26)
  - Lord Roland Gower Biography (Unpublished)
    - Correspondence and Manuscripts
      - Correspondence
        - not dated (Box 27)
        - 1965-78 (Box 27)
        - 1982-86 (Box 27)
      - Drafts (Folders 1-3) (Box 27, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Notes (Box 28)
    - Photocopied Material and Microfilm
      - Photocopied Material
        - My Reminiscences vols. 1, 2 by Gower (Box 29)
        - Old Diaries, by Gower (Box 29)
      - Microfilm
        - Diary of the Duchess of Sutherland, 1864 (Box 29)
        - Diary of Lord Gower, 1903-05 (Box 29)
  - Misc. Articles
    - Correspondence, Drafts and Related Materials (Folders 1-2) (Box 30, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Correspondence, Drafts and Related Materials (Folders 3-5) (Box 31, Folder 3 to 5)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Photographs and Negatives (of Benkovitz) (Box 32)
    - Microfilm (Box 32)
    - Magazines and Exhibition Catalogues (Box 32)